<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Alexander G. Hurley</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Alexander G. Hurley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Alexander G. Hurley</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open source software development</title>
      <link>/project/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/software/</guid>
      <description>Research is generally highly domain and application specific and therefore often requires unique and tailored data analyses approaches. While specialized, many approaches are well established within scientific communities, yet are applied on a variety of platforms in a non-standardized manner. By developing and distributing well-documented, open-source software, such analyses can become more accessible, aiding in advancing science toward more reproducibility.
My software is written in R (for statistical computing) and freely available via my GitHub repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecohydrological functioning of shallow Boreal Plain wetlands (PhD)</title>
      <link>/project/phd-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/phd-research/</guid>
      <description>Background My research focuses on the interplay of hydrology and ecology of shallow, ephemeral wetlands in the Boreal Plain (Alberta, Canada). In particular, I am delineating processes that allow surplus water generation in a sub-humid environment, linking plant community dynamics and vegetation structure with water movement at multiple scales (i.e. leaf to catchment). With this research I hope to inform the reclamation of mine closure sites in the Athabasca Oil Sands Region, where the reconstruction of ecosystems often requires estimating delicate water balances to meet future, often conflicting goals (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>