<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Alexander G. Hurley</title>
    <link>/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks on Alexander G. Hurley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Alexander G. Hurley</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the ecohydrological role of cryptic, forested wetlands in the Boreal Plain (Canada): Local-scale effects with a potential regional impact</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-egu-wetland-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-egu-wetland-forest/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R in Hydrology (SC1.19/HS12.4)</title>
      <link>/talk/2018-egu-rhydro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2018-egu-rhydro/</guid>
      <description>Join us for a great short course demonstrating latest approaches, methods and workflows in hydrology and data analyses related to R. See below for the course&amp;rsquo;s description.
Wondering why or how to use R in hydrology? You’re in the right place! In this short course, you will learn how R is applied in a range of hydrological research settings from a number of guest lecturers.
Topics for 2018 include: - Recent R updates and packages - Accessing hydrological data using web APIs, with a demo of the rnrfa package - Reading and visualising large-scale gridded data (netCDF) - Processing, modelling and visualising hydrological data in R (tidyverse) - Hydrological modelling (airGR) and teaching modelling (airGRteaching) - An introduction to the smires and lfstat (low flow statistics) packages</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alumnus Experience</title>
      <link>/talk/imae-alumnus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/imae-alumnus/</guid>
      <description>Being selected for a spot on the Erasmus Mundus Master&amp;rsquo;s Course &amp;ldquo;International Master&amp;rsquo;s in Applied Ecology&amp;rdquo; in 2013 was a great privilege and provided once-in-a-lifetime experiences and outstanding education. It was a great honor to be invited back to the graduation ceremony in 2016, one year after I completed the program, to share these experiences - as well as some insight on the path I chose after - to graduating and newly enrolling students during the Farewell Congress in Poitiers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatio-temporal dynamics of evapotranspiration from forested, ephemeral wetlands</title>
      <link>/talk/2017-egu-et-wetland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/2017-egu-et-wetland/</guid>
      <description>This presentation featured work on partitioning atmospheric water fluxes from the subcanopy of a forested wetland in the Boreal Plain and discussed initial results on processes in the plant-soil continuum that reduce water losses under dry conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>